activemelody.com 2019-02-04

# Privacy Policy

ActiveMelody.com is a supportive community of guitar enthusiasts.  We are committed to maintaining the trust and confidence of our visitors to our web site. Active Melody is does not sell, rent or trade information with third parties. This notice provides information about when and why we collect your personal information, how we use it, the limited conditions under which we may disclose it to others and how we keep it secure. 

## What personal data we collect and why we collect it

We collect information you provide directly to us. For example, we collect information when you create an account, participate in a forum, post a video or yourself, make a purchase, complete a survey, request customer support or otherwise communicate with us.

### Comments

When members leave comments on the Active Melody website we collect the comments themselves, and the member’s IP address.  We track IP addresses so that we can block spam that is posted on the site.

### Forms

When you become a member, we collect your first name, last name and your email address so that we can correspond with you.  This personal data will not only be stored in the website’s database but also in [https://mailchimp.com/](https://mailchimp.com/), the application we use to send our newsletters and campaign.

### Registration

Active Melody does not require you to register  to view portions of the website including the first part of weekly guitar lessons.  In order to gain access to the social tools like profiles and forums, registration is mandatory.  We collect your name and email address and require to to accept our Membership Agreement. Premium membership allows access to the second part of weekly lessons and a variety of bonus materials including jam tracks and tablature.  In addition to collecting your name and email address, we also collect your credit card number and address to process payments. 

### Cookies

If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.

If you have an account and you log in to this site, we will set a temporary cookie to determine if your browser accepts cookies. This cookie contains no personal data and is discarded when you close your browser.

When you log in, we will also set up several cookies to save your login information and your screen display choices. Login cookies last for two days, and screen options cookies last for a year. If you select “Remember Me”, your login will persist for two weeks. If you log out of your account, the login cookies will be removed.  If you edit or publish comments or videos on the forum, an additional cookie will be saved in your browser. This cookie includes no personal data and simply indicates the post ID of the article you just edited. It expires after 1 day.

### Google Analytics

We use Google Analytics to track visitors on this site.  Google Analytics uses cookies to collect this data. In order to be compliant with the new regulation Google included a [data processing amendment](https://www.google.com/analytics/terms/dpa/dataprocessingamendment_20130906.html).  The data we collect will be processed anonymously and “Data sharing” is disabled.  We don’t use other Google services in combination with Google Analytics cookies.

### MailChimp

We use [https://mailchimp.com/](https://mailchimp.com/) for our newsletter and email campaigns.  MailChimp is one of the best marketing automation platform and is GDPR compliant. They have a campaign builder that makes it easy to create email templates.  In MailChimp we only store your email address and when provide your name. With your permission, we may send you emails about our store, new products and other updates.

### Akismet

We collect information about visitors who comment on Sites that use our Akismet anti-spam service. Akismet is a spam filtering service that filters spam from comments, trackbacks, and contact form messages. The information we collect depends includes the commenter’s IP address, user agent, referrer, and Site URL (along with other information directly provided by the commenter such as their name, username, email address, and the comment itself). You can review [Akismet’s privacy policy](https://automattic.com/privacy/). 

## Embedded content from other websites

Active Melody  may include content like videos, images and music that resides on other sites but is embedded within our site. Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.  These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

## Who we share your data with

We don’t share or rent our member’s names or email addresses with third party marketers.  We don’t share member’s self-published content unless we ask you first. Occasionally we highlight a member’s performance on social media, but we won’t do so without first obtaining written consent from you.  We use Mail Chimp as our email service provider. You can review [Mail Chimp’s privacy policy. ](https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/)

When you purchase a membership on ActiveMelody.com, your personal data are shared with PayPal and Stripe who are vendors that process payments.  We do not store or have access to your credit card number. 

You can check their privacy policies using the links below:

**PayPal:** [https://www.paypal.com/us/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full](https://www.paypal.com/us/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full)

**Stripe:** [https://stripe.com/us/privacy/](https://stripe.com/us/privacy/)

## How long we retain your data

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.  For users that register on our website (if any), we also store the personal information they provide in their user profile. All users can see, edit, or delete their personal information at any time (except they cannot change their username). Website administrators can also see and edit that information.

## What rights you have over your data

If you have an account on this site, or have left comments, you can request a report of data we hold about you.  You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.  To make inquiries, change or receive your data, contact support@activemelody.com

## Security

To protect your personal information, we take reasonable precautions and follow industry best practices to make sure it is not inappropriately lost, misused, accessed, disclosed, altered or destroyed.  If you provide us with your credit card information, the information is encrypted using secure socket layer technology (SSL) and stored with a encryption. Although no method of transmission over the Internet or electronic storage is 100% secure, we follow all PCI-DSS requirements and implement additional generally accepted industry standards.

## Minors

We do not provide services or sell products to children. However, we may sell products to adults for use by children. Regardless of the intended end user of our products, only adults should purchase anything from our website. If a product we offer is legal only for adults to use or possess, no adult should purchase the product for illegal use or possession by a minor.

If you are below the age of 18, you may use our website only with the permission, active involvement, and supervision of an adult parent or legal guardian. If you are a minor, please do not provide us or other website visitors with any personal information.

## Changes to this privacy policy

We reserve the right to modify this privacy policy at any time, so please review it frequently. Changes and clarifications will take effect immediately upon their posting on the website. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you here that it has been updated, so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we use and/or disclose it.

## Contact information

**  
Questions or Concerns**

Any questions or concerns about this website privacy policy should be brought to our attention by sending an email to Support@activemelody.com and providing us with information relating to your concern.

You may also mail your concerns to us at the following address:

**Active Melody** **  
****P.O. Box 159** **  
****Franklin, Tennessee 37064** **  
****United States**
